Let's use programmatic assessment now to detect and
لنستخدم التقييم البرمجي الآن لاستكشاف
document the final tidiness issue in this dataset.
مشكلة الترتيب النهائية وتوثيقها في مجموعة البيانات هذه.
Programmatic assessment can be handy for the third tidiness requirement,
يمكن أن يكون التقييم البرمجي مفيدًا لمطلب الترتيب الثالث،
which is that each type of observational unit forms a table.
وهو أن كل نوع من وحدة الملاحظة يشكل جدولًا.
This requirement focuses on the columns of
يركز هذا المطلب على أعمدة
the dataset across all tables, if there are multiple.
مجموعة البيانات عبر جميع الجداول، إذا كانت هناك عدة أعمدة.
Which makes programmatic assessment especially useful if
مما يجعل التقييم البرمجي مفيدًا بشكل خاص
the dataset you're assessing has lots of columns and/or lots of tables.
إذا كانت مجموعة البيانات التي تقومون بتقييمها تحتوي على الكثير من الأعمدة و/أو الكثير من الجداول.
This makes visual assessment harder because resizing windows,
وهذا يجعل التقييم البصري أكثر صعوبة لأن تغيير حجم النوافذ،
switching between spreadsheet tabs,
والتبديل بين علامات تبويب جداول البيانات،
scrolling through a Pandas data frame,
والتمرير خلال إطار بيانات Pandas،
etc., is just kind of annoying.
وما إلى ذلك أصبح أمرًا مزعجًا.
With programmatic assessments like the dot_info method,
باستخدام التقييمات البرمجية مثل طريقة dot_info،
we can get a quick glance at all of our column names across all tables,
يمكننا إلقاء نظرة سريعة على جميع أسماء الأعمدة عبر جميع الجداول،
and also the data types within them.
وكذلك على أنواع البيانات داخلها.
So we'll reuse our dot_info cells here for patients,
حسنًا، سنعيد استخدام خلايا dot_info هنا للمرضى،
treatments and adverse reactions.
والعلاجات، وردود الفعل العكسية.
So take a look through these column headers and
لذا يمكنكم إلقاء نظرة على عناوين الأعمدة هذه
really think about which headers should belong in what table.
والتفكير حقًا في أي العناوين يجب أن تنتمي إلى أي جدول.
How many tables do we need to make this clinical trial dataset as a whole?
كم عدد الجداول التي نحتاجها لجعل مجموعة بيانات التجربة الإكلينيكية هذه كمجموعة كاملة؟